BABATUNDE OLUWASEGUN ADEKUNLE

oluwasegunababatunde@gmail.com | +2348034372743

SUMMARY

Energetic and curiosity-driven software developer with 5+ years of experience writing top-quality clean code for high-paced businesses. Eager to support organization in modernizing its world-class products and delivering an incredible user experience. In previous roles created a backend library for enterprise scale applications used in to process payments.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Agent and IT Consultant: March 2016 – Present

Position: Full-Stack Software Developer

- Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions on Mobile, Web, and Desktop apps like:
 - o Facial Student Attendance
 - AXIS API (Banking system Web App, API, and Database)
 - Reconciliation App (To compare two excel file and point out where they have similar or different data)
 - Mobile Apps with Ads Integration for earning.
 - o Online Car Sales
 - o Restaurant Management System
 - Stock management System
 - Online Student Assignment Submission
 - o Airline Reservation System
 - E-Voting
 - Estate/Hotel Management System
 - Image Steganography, and so on...

Affixcity Partner Solution, UAE: January 2022 - Present

Position: Full-Stack Software Developer

- Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions on Mobile and Web apps.
- Database management on MYSQL Server and Firebase.
- Develop E-Commerce Mobile Apps for customer, partner, and verifications.
- Effectively managed data sync across all platform implemented.

SupplyingTech IT Solution, USA: January 2022 - Present

Position: Full-Stack Software Developer

- Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions on Mobile and Web apps.
- Database management on MYSQL Server and Firebase.
- Develop Bot Mobile Apps for trading Automation across different platforms.
- Effectively managed data sync across all platform implemented.

Em&Em Info-Tech Solution, Offa, Kwara, Nigeria: August 2018 – Present

Position: Full-Stack Software Developer and Programming Instructor

- Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions on Desktop and Web apps.
- Database management on MSSQL Server and MS Access.
- Instruct young programmers on web and desktop app development using C#.NET, VB.NET and ASP.NET.
- Effectively managed approximately 50 young programmers daily.

LANGUAGES

Visual Studio and Xamarin: - XAML, C#.NET, VB.NET, ASP.NET CORE MVC, ASP.NET FRAMEWORK MVC, ASP.NET RAZOR MVC, ASP.NET BLAZOR MVC, Progressive Web App (PWA).

Android Studio and Flutter: - XAML, JAVA, KOTLIN, DART.

Visual Studio Code: - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS, Typescript.

Others: - Swift (XCode), MS SQL SERVER, MYSQL, Firebase, Supabase, MongoDB, Google Ads, et al.

	EDUCATION	
B.Sc., Compute	er Science: In-View	
•	National Open University of Nigeria, Ilorin, Kwara state, Nigeria.	(2021 – Present)
ND, Computer	Science	(2017-2019)

3.60, Distinction Class Honours, Lower Division

• Federal Polytechnic Offa, Offa, Kwara state, Nigeria.

CERTIFICATIONS, TRAINING & AWARDS			
Jobberman Soft Skills Training Certification	2021		
 MegaRich Consults & Networks LTD Certification of Proficiency 	2018		
 NASS Overall Best Student, Computer Science 	2019		
NACCOSS Best Student in ND	2018/19		
 Second Runner at NACCOSS Software Exhibition Programme 	2018/19		

HOBBIES

- Skateboarding, Biking, and Hiking.
- Video Gaming.
- Traveling, Vacationing and exploring IT Solutions.
- Training young people in programming.

REFEREES

Available on request